Cabot, Lawrence; Papers apap234
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Lawrence A. Cabot Papers
1964-1965
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Cabot, Lawrence A.
apap234
1.6 cubic ft.
The Lawrence A. Cabot Papers document Cabot's service in the New York State Assembly where he served for one term in 1964-1965. The collection includes correspondence, subject files, and legislation from his tenure.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Lawrence Cabot initially donated his papers to Syracuse University in 1966. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
Lawrence A. Cabot was born on May 17th, 1919. He attended City College and served with the 2nd Armored Division in World War II. A Democrat, Cabot lived in Ardsley, New York. He was elected to the New York State Assembly in 1964 and represented the Westchester County Second District for one term. During his political career, he served on the Claims, Internal Affairs, Revision, and Villages committees. Cabot was also chairman of the Ardsley Democratic Committee and vice-chairman of the Greenburg Democratic Committee.
Scope and Contents
The Lawrence A. Cabot Papers consist of both subject files and legislation related to Cabot's service in the New York State Assembly from 1964-1965. The subject files contain primarily correspondence although there are also newspaper clippings, press releases, and one map. The legislation includes bills that Cabot sponsored while in the Assembly and resolutions he was involved with. The legislation files frequently include supplemental materials such as correspondence and newspaper clippings.
Please note the archivist retained the original arrangment of the collection. Therefore there is a "resolutions" folder containing resolutions from local governments in Cabot's district in Series 1 as well as individual folders containing resolutions in Series 2. The folder in Series 1 simply contains the resolutions themselves while the files in Series 2 generally contain the resolutions as well as supplemental materials.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Subject Files, 1964-1965
Series 2 - Legislation, 1964-1965
Series 1 is arranged alphabetically by subject while Series 2 is arranged chronologically, first by bill number and then by resolution number.
Politics and Politicians; Politicians--New York (State); New York (State)--Politics and government; Westchester County (N.Y.); Bills (legislative records); Clippings; Correspondence; Files by subject; Legislative Records; Cabot, Lawrence A.; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly. Committee of Claims; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly. Internal Affairs Committee; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly. Revision Committee; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly. Villages Committee
- Subject Files, 1964-1965; Undated; 1; 1.0 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains a variety of subject files ranging from air pollution to sales tax. Cabot also kept his general correspondence and news releases with subject files.
  - Aid to Education, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1-2)
  - Air Pollution, 1964-1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Auto Registration Tax and Gasoline Tax, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Capital Punishment, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Cigarette Tax, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Dobbs Ferry (Letters Patent), 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Fisheries, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Form Letters and Lists, Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Greenburgh Housing, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Hospitals, Union Berking Bill, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Hudson River (Con Edison), 1964-1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Invitations, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Memos, 1964 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence (A-H), 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15-18)
  - General Correspondence (I-Q), 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19-21)
  - General Correspondence (R-Z), 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22-23)
  - Newspaper Mailing List, Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - News Releases, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Off-track Betting, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Police Fire Pensions (separate), 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Pornography, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - R.R. (New Haven) (N.Y. Central), 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Repeal of Drinking Age, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Requested Comments from School Districts, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Resolutions, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Rosetti Bill AI-1439, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Sales Tax, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34-35)
  - Tuckahoe Urban Renewal Bill, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Veteran Hospitals, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Westchester Board of Supervisors, 1964-1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
- Legislation, 1964-1965; 2; .6 cu. ft.
  Arranged chronologically by bill number and then by resolution number.
  This series consists of legislation Cabot sponsored. Each file entitled "bill" includes the legislative bill and many folders also have supplemental materials such as correspondence or clippings. The resolutions files contain copies of resolutions submitted to the New York State Legislature or local town boards, reports, clippings, and correspondence.
  - Bill 918, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 1)
  - Bill 1014, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 2)
  - Bill 1015, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 3)
  - Bill 1016, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 4)
  - Bill 1238, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 5)
  - Bill 1374 (multi-sponsored), 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 6)
  - Bill 1426, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 7)
  - Bill 1630, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 8)
  - Bill 1631, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 9)
  - Bill 1632, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 10)
  - Bill 1922, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 11)
  - Bill 1923, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 12)
  - Bill 1924, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 13)
  - Bill 1925, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 14)
  - Bill 1926, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 15)
  - Bill 1927, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 16)
  - Bill 2093, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 17)
  - Bill 2094, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 18)
  - Bill 2154, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 19)
  - Bill 2155, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 20)
  - Bill 2156, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 21)
  - Bill 2157, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 22)
  - Bill 2158, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 23)
  - Bill 2159, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 24)
  - Bill 2438, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 25)
  - Bill 2439, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 26)
  - Bill 2440, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 27)
  - Bill 2441, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 28)
  - Bill 2442, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 29)
  - Bill 2658, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 30)
  - Bill 2941, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 31)
  - Bill 3516, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 32)
  - Bill 3765, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 33)
  - Bill 3766, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 34)
  - Bill 3771 (multi-sponsored), 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 35)
  - Bill 3821, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 36)
  - Bill 3822, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 37)
  - Bill 3823, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 38)
  - Bill 4006 (Multi-sponsored), 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 39)
  - Bills 4256-4263, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 40)
  - Bill 4264, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 41)
  - Bill 4265, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 42)
  - Bill 4266, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 43)
  - Bill 4267, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 44)
  - Bill 4326, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 45)
  - Bill 4327, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 46)
  - Bill 4468, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 47)
  - Bill 4469, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 48)
  - Bill 4470, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 49)
  - Bill 4471, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 50)
  - Bill 5025, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Legislation), Folder 51)
  - Bill 5085, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 1)
  - Bill 5098, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 2)
  - Bill 5259, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 3)
  - Bill 5681 (Multi-sponsored), 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 4)
  - Bill 5903, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 5)
  - Bill 5951, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 6)
  - Bill 5984, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 7)
  - Bill 5986, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 8)
  - Bill 6133, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 9)
  - Bill 6164, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 10)
  - Resolution II, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 11)
  - Resolution 57, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 12)
  - Resolutions 84-85-86, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 13)
  - Resolution 87, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 14)
  - Resolution 89, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 15)
  - Resolution 120-121-141, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 16)
  - Resolution 282, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 17)
  - Resolution 301, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Legislation), Folder 18)